Here, thanks for waiting.
Thanks!
Happy birthday!
Oh, thank you!
This is from us!
Hey, what are they doing?
It's a birthday celebration.
Huh, how festive.
So, what's a birthday?
Huh?
The problem is that Blade doesn't
know when his own birthday is.
That means we can't celebrate it.
Truth be told, we don't
know his exact age, either.
He could already stand and walk
by the time they found him.
We assumed he was one year old,
which would make him 17 now.
Oh, in that case,
do you know the day that they found him?
I believe the Great— Wait, no!
Blade told me about it was once.
It's coming up in about a month.
I heard that when they found him,
he was holding a sword.
Ah, so that's why he's named Blade.
Does that mean he'd be Lance
if it had been a lance?
Club if it was a club?
Man, that's hilarious!
Now all we need is something
Blade would like.
What would he want?
How about tonkatsu curry?
I'm pretty sure that won't do.
I-I know that!
I just can't think of anything else.
I see!
Tonkatsu curry as a present!
Nothing wrong with some tasty food!
Everyone loves it! I do, too!
Um, Your Majesty...
He can get tonkatsu curry in the cafeteria.
What if it wasn't normal, then?
Yes!
You just need to prepare a special,
royal tonkatsu curry for him!
Huh?
Now, behold!
This is the Royal Pantry,
the pride of our kingdom!
Hey, what's going on?!
You'll be getting some
hands-on training in here.
Go on and eat your fill of delicious foods!
What?!
I look in your eyes, and I'm met with
A brand-new me and dream
Bravery? Naturally?
Polar opposites within the heart
But, you know, wanting to have both
That's the saga of human nature
Oh no, don't mind me
Go ahead, and so on, you know the rest
A little more? Wait, even harder?!
Going overboard much?
Those selfish emotions deep down
Bringing them to light is what friendship's about
Spending adolescence duking it out with pals
I don't wanna lose
We're off to the cutting edge moment
Fight with best friends, and leave no regrets
You should laugh, since you look best with a smile
On the ropes?! No matter what we face, et cetera
Just sit back and enjoy it
Whatever may come, I'll be here to protect you
Episode 10
I'm Looking for
Something
Tastier than Me
What are you gonna make us do this time?
Um, we're underneath the castle, aren't we?
Could this be some sort of ancient,
grand magic that collapses space on itself?
Those doors will not open until the
required condition has been met!
The condition to open the doors...
is to consume a combined total
of 11.3 billion calories.
100 million calories per person?!
So we have to survive out here until then?
Sniff, sniff...
I smell lots of tasty things!
Exactly!
There are ingredients preserved here
that date back to the age of the gods.
We say preserved, but all the plants and
animals here are uncontrollably violent,
so in reality, they've been
allowed to run rampant.
Thin out their numbers a bit, won't you?
Hey, that's a job for a group
of hero-level warriors!
Are you really gonna make us students do it?
Right, Earnest?
Okay!
Here we go, everyone!
First, we need to establish a campsite!
Yep.
Parent!
I can hardly wait!
Huh?
Hey! Over here!
This way! Right here!
Magnificent!
Now, get it in the pit trap...
Leonard!
Hey, why me?!
Ah, I guess it thinks Claire looks tastier.
Watch out! Mademois—
Leonard!
Fighting weaklings is no fun, but...
What happened?!
Hey! Are you alright?!
Well, if I must.
Satan Levin.
Yes! Now we have food!
Oh, it's already over?
Open the gates!
There!
Okay, all good?
If we build more lookout towers here,
we'll be equipped to
confront outside invaders!
What about the repairs to the southern wall?
Yeah, we just finished.
I understand.
Everyone!
It's almost time for dinner,
so work hard until then!
Maybe the king came up with
a good exercise this time.
Don't stare too much.
Okay, I won't look.
You're really not looking?
You're the one who told me not to.
Hey.
What were you like as a child?
Well, you know...
Like, do you remember any celebrations?
Huh?
I basically spent 24 hours a day fighting.
Eh?
Were you training to become
stronger or something?
Nope, just fighting for my life.
You'll die if you're weaker
than whoever attacks you.
So getting stronger was just a fact of life.
Become stronger or die.
I was faced with that decision every day.
What are you saying?
What?
You asked what I was like as a kid.
Hey, Blade, I...
Wait, Claire!
Don't go any further than that!
Huh? You two...
Y-Y-You...
You were watching?!
We sure did get used to living here.
I wonder how many calories we've consumed.
Including today's share, we have
reached 47% of our calorie target.
According to my high-spec
powers of calculation,
we will most certainly meet our
target by the designated date.
Very impressive!
It seems your survival
exercise is going well.
Survival?
Has the king forgotten the original goal?
Ah...
As you've worked to survive,
you've all grown so much,
and it seems the original task
might be a little too easy for you.
And so!
I've prepared a special challenge!
I want you all to gather the
ingredients listed here!
How are these different from the
ingredients we've faced so far?
Will you accept the challenge?
Okay, let's go get that reward!
That's...
Cabbage!
Yep, cabbage.
Cabbage.
I don't like veggies!
That's an Emperor Cabbage!
Emperor?
The cabbage cultivar originally
stored in the Royal Pantry
went feral in these hostile conditions,
and underwent adaptive evolution!
I'll burn it to a crisp!
You can't.
We need it to be raw.
Ah, that's right.
Everyone!
Let's reinforce our defenses
and charge in all at once!
Why raw?
Whoa!
Understood, my lord.
Sure, let's do it!
Everyone's really fired up for some reason.
We've captured the Emperor Cabbage!
There's no mistaking it.
That's Boxing Corn.
I get the corn part...
But what's boxing?
An ancient contest where you
fight with only your fists.
Hey! You wanna go?
No, Blade.
Eh?
If you don't follow the procedure for
defeating it, it won't taste good.
You can only use your fists.
You're kidding me!
Um...
You can capture it if the
match goes to a decision,
and you let it burn out to pure white ash.
What does decision refer to here?
So I can't knock it out?!
Wait!
If it's a fist fight, shouldn't
Sophie or Iona fight instead?
No substitutions allowed.
The bell has already rung.
H-Hey! Still—
In that case, here I come!
We've managed to capture the Boxing Corn.
Good work, Blade.
Wait, you too?!
Go!
What's going on here?
The spice is so strong,
it's leaching out into the air.
What a sorry sight you all are.
You will not be able to
become top-class like that.
No, just look at you.
These are not tears.
This is cleaning solution for my eyeballs!
Go!
Sniff, sniff...
Those sunflowers are giving
off a tasty smell, too!
Um...
Those are Sunflowers.
They can—
This isn't good!
It looks like they have the ability to
store sunlight and then discharge it!
Interesting.
I'll show these lowly Sunflowers
what happens when they oppose me!
We dragons won't lose, either!
I'll just cheer you on, yep.
It's a carrot.
Yes, a carrot.
Is it going to bite or spit fire at us?
No signs of movement.
Guess I'll try pulling it out.
Hup!
Ah! H-Hold it right there!
Huh?
What? A psychological attack?!
There's some very tiny writing at the bottom.
A Greater Mandora will
shriek when it's uprooted.
Hey!
It says here that its
scream is a lethal curse!
Good thing we noticed before it was too late.
What do we do about this?
Iona?
I am not human, so curses meant for
living organisms have no effect.
Hup.
Is it over?
It should be safe now.
That reminds me... I don't really like carrots.
Huh? Really?
Well, I don't mind eating
them when they're in a dish.
I-I see...
Yes!
You're all doing splendidly!
What remarkable progress!
Thanks to you, the ecosystem of the
Royal Pantry has undergone a drastic change!
The population will be about one-tenth
what it was for the next few years.
Huh?
Is that a good thing?
Won't they go extinct?
They wouldn't give us so much trouble
if we could make them go extinct.
They're just like the weeds in your garden.
Don't sweat the small stuff!
Yes!
Tomorrow, you face the final ingredient!
The moment of truth!
Look at this big tree!
We are at the base of the main trunk.
The energy leaked from the engine is
most highly concentrated in this area.
In other words, it's the
spot richest in nutrients.
It makes sense that the creature
known as the king of the pantry
would choose to occupy this location.
Here it comes, everyone!
So this is the king!
The list simply says it's the Beast King.
Also that it's strong and tasty.
That's way too vague!
What's the point of youth
without hazards and adversity?
It's only after you've overcome those
that triumph and glory await!
Blade!
You can do it!
Okay! Everyone!
Eh?
What?!
That's a Behemoth.
Oh?
I had planned for beef to be the main dish,
but Behemoth meat is a fine choice, too.
Go on, hunt it down!
It defeated the old king, so there's
no problem calling it the Beast King!
Behemoth meat is far tastier
than beef, you know!
Hey, now, that's outrageous!
Hmm, does a Behemoth really taste that good?
Eh?
What a relief.
We were about to make something
so disappointing the main dish!
Don't you all agree?
Huh? Why?!
How reassuring!
How very reassuring!
O sword! Consume my flesh!
Use it as thy power!
Everyone! Here we go!
Alright!
Claire, over here as well!
Yeah, leave them to me!
Now!
Did we get it?
It had no effect?!
Oh, no!
God Technique! Absolute Defense!
Blade!
There's only one technique
that can take it down.
I see.
But how?
It's not a technique you can use
with only 15% of your power available.
Yeah, it requires at least 30%.
Which is why I need your assistance, Mao.
Please take some of my spiritual energy!
Interesting.
You wish to use me as a vessel?
Incredible.
However, this way is faster.
I'm about to overflow.
You've filled me to the brim.
R-Right...
How long are you gonna keep us waiting?!
R-Right!
Now, if I hone my fighting spirit...
Everyone! It's almost time!
You can count on us.
10 seconds, Iona.
Yes.
Interconnect link complete.
Transmitting power.
Artificial Great Hero Power:
Gravity Manipulation.
Target confirmed.
Firing Positronium Cannon.
We can't fully immobilize it!
We'll stop that thing!
Here we go, Demon King.
Very well, Great Hero.
Stand back, everyone!
If good be in my path, strike down all good.
If evil be in my path, strike down all evil.
Holy Demon Blade!
This was the technique you defeated me with.
I can't use it...
by myself anymore, though...
It's thanks to... you taking half...
What, Great Hero?
Are you going to die?
No, I'm not.
I'm just tired.
Also...
Also?
I'm so hungry!
Just you wait, then.
For what...
It's gone up by 3%.
What?
You can use up to 18% of your strength now.
Why hasn't it gone down?
Eating properly, getting moderate exercise...
Also, taking some time to
recuperate probably helped.
I wonder if it was the open-air baths...
By the way, have you eaten lunch?
Ah! That's right, I haven't yet!
I'm off to go eat!
Happy birthday, Blade!
Today is your birthday.
Huh? It is?
For people who don't know
when they were born,
they usually celebrate their birthday
on the day they were fostered.
Huh? What?
You were taken in on this day, 17 years ago!
Master.
Humans should celebrate their
birth and annihilation.
You're all going to celebrate it?
For me?
Now you're the same age as me.
You were older than me?!
That's right!
So show some respect!
Blade really never had anyone
celebrate his birthday.
No, I haven't.
Um, what's this?
We were all brainstorming.
To figure out what to get
you for your birthday.
And Anna suggested this.
I thought you might like it.
Tonkatsu curry!
Let me point out that everything
is from the Royal Pantry!
Made with the ultimate gourmet ingredients,
it's a one-of-a-kind, special tonkatsu curry!
We got help from His Majesty as well.
Why, it was all quite amusing!
So you all did this for me...
Well? Not going to eat it?
Well, I'm just not used
to this kind of thing...
What's wrong?
What reason is there to hold back?
Someone told me a long time ago.
That boys should never cry.
You fool!
Manly tears are meant for
an occasion like this!
In the name of the king, Gilgamesh Soulmaker,
I hereby retract any past statements
that men shouldn't cry!
The sunny disposition that brings a smile to your face
Go ahead and cry!
As well as the heroic sense of justice
They may be a part of me, but that's not all there is
Thank you, everyone!
This tastes really good!
That image of me
Has taken on a life of its own
Here, for the first time...
Hey, wait up
Won't you be friends with me?
I feel like I've truly
been born into this world!
Let's shake hands, another self of mine
The wounds we cannot bear alone
The dangers that we keep hidden
We're all hiding them within
Standing ready to strike
The shadow lurking beneath the light
The muffled sounds coming from my lips
They make me feel that I am alive
It's a sign
Next Time
The Sophie Series (Part 1)